let's look at the solution to our global
and local miss rate quiz for a level 1
cache when we say that it has a 90
percent hit rate we don't have to
specify whether it's a global or local
hit rate because it's the same it's
local miss rate is the number of misses
divided by the number of accesses to
this cache its global miss rate is the
number of misses divided by all the
accesses that the processor makes but
because all these accesses go to this
cache they are the same and they're both
10% because that's what percentage of
all processor accesses misses in this
cache and that is also the percentage of
things that reach this cache that Miss
in it for a level 2 cache things are
different
it hits for 50% of l1 misses that means
that it misses for half of the l1 misses
so it's local miss rate is 50% of all
the things that reach this cache and
those are only l1 misses half of them
hit and half of them miss but it's
global miss rate is only 5% because only
10% of the accesses get to this cache
and half of that misses so when we
express the misses in terms of all the
accesses that the processor made only 5%
of all processor accesses end up missing
in the l2 cache